Armstrong-Dunn; Collection mss149
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
Armstrong-Dunn Collection
1819-1886
Undated
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
mss149
.2 cubic ft.
This collection contains 19th century correspondence and financial records created by the Armstrong and Dunn families of Johnsburg in Warren County, New York. There is more material from the Dunn family than that of the Armstrongs, especially from John Dunn.
Content Description
This collection contains 19th century materials created by the Armstrong and Dunn families of Johnsburg in Warren County, New York. It includes correspondence and financials. There is more material from the Dunn family present in the collection, especially from John Dunn.
Arrangement of the Collection
The collection is organized alphabetically. There are no series.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Vincent Schaefer donated this collection to the University Libraries, M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, along with his own papers sometime between 1979 and 1993. Schaefer noted that he found the Armstrong-Dunn Collection in August 1935 in the "Old Armstrong Homestead near Johnsburgh on road from Johnsburgh southward."
Access
Access to this colleciton is unrestricted.
Biographical Note
The Armstrongs and Dunns were both families in Johnsburg, Warren County, New York. John Dunn (1793-1856) was born in Greenwich, Conneticut and served as town supervisor in 1838. His wife Catherine (1823-1878) was born in Wilton, Saratoga County.
Dunn Family; Armstrong Family; Johnsburg (N.Y.) -- History
- Accounts of John W. Armstrong, Undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Accounts of John Dunn, 1819-1820; 1825; 1830 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Accounts of Catherine Dunn, 1874-1875 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Accounts, Unknown Household, 1859 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Correspondence of John D. Armstrong, 1886; Undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Correspondence of and Presumably of John Dunn, 1819; 1831 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Correspondence of J. R. Dunn, 1864 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Correspondence of Sarah Dunn, 1855 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Correspondence of William Dunn, 1863 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Correspondence to Warren, Sent from Point Lookout, Last Name Unknown, 1864 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Deed, Undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
- John Dunn, Witness to Bond/Legal Agreement, 1826 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Program Outline with Reading by John Dunn, Undated (Box 1, Folder 13)